Hello, welcome to class. Again, welcome. My name is David Brown and this is going to be an original combo reading writing and grammar class. I'm glad that you're all here. Have a seat everybody. Welcome.
안녕하세요, 수업에 오신 것을 환영합니다. 다시 한번 환영합니다. 제 이름은 데이비드 브라운이고, 이 수업은 독창적인 읽기, 쓰기, 문법 통합 수업이 될 것입니다. 여러분 모두 여기 와주셔서 기쁩니다. 모두 자리에 앉아주세요. 환영합니다.
Hey, Hector. How are you?
안녕하세요, 헥터 학생. 잘 지내시나요?
Just fine. How are you?
네, 잘 지냅니다. 선생님은 어떠신가요?
I'm doing great. Thank you.
저는 아주 잘 지내고 있습니다. 감사합니다.
Welcome. Welcome.
환영합니다. 환영합니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I see that you selected a class about arguments. Would you like to learn how to be more persuasive in today's class?
주장에 관한 수업을 선택하신 것을 확인했습니다. 오늘 수업에서 더 설득력 있게 되는 법을 배우고 싶으신가요?
I would like to. I would love to actually because that's a very important thing to do when you speak another language.
네, 배우고 싶습니다. 사실 정말 배우고 싶어요, 왜냐하면 다른 언어를 말할 때 그것이 매우 중요한 일이기 때문입니다.
Yeah, the basic question of this is what do we want and how do we get that? And communication is the means in which we acquire the things that we want.
네, 이것의 기본적인 질문은 '우리는 무엇을 원하는가, 그리고 어떻게 그것을 얻을 수 있는가?'입니다. 그리고 의사소통은 우리가 원하는 것을 얻는 수단입니다.
So learning to be persuasive is just really an amazing soft skills to learn.
그래서 설득력 있게 되는 법을 배우는 것은 정말 놀라운 소프트 스킬입니다.
And there are procedures that we can follow in order to persuade effectively. So in today's lesson, we'll talk about persuading effectively and about some grammar reading and writing task that can help us to persuade formally.
그리고 효과적으로 설득하기 위해 우리가 따를 수 있는 절차들이 있습니다. 그래서 오늘 수업에서는 효과적으로 설득하는 방법과 공식적으로 설득하는 데 도움이 될 수 있는 몇 가지 문법, 읽기, 쓰기 과제에 대해 이야기할 것입니다.
We have this concept of cohesion and cohesion is when something is whole.
우리에게는 'cohesion'(응집성)이라는 개념이 있는데, 응집성이란 무언가가 전체적으로 완전한 상태를 의미합니다.
In order to make a good argument, we need to have all the parts of the argument.
좋은 주장을 하기 위해서는 주장의 모든 부분을 갖추어야 합니다.
And we also need the argument to be smooth. It has to flow. So we have cohesion and those two concepts that we'll talk about a little bit today.
그리고 또한 주장이 매끄러워야 합니다. 흐름이 있어야 하죠. 그래서 우리에게는 'cohesion'(응집성)과 'flow'(흐름)라는 두 가지 개념이 있는데, 오늘 이것들에 대해 조금 이야기할 것입니다.
So let's explore how we can achieve this.
그럼 어떻게 이것을 달성할 수 있는지 탐구해 봅시다.
So I have an image on the screen here. It says from jumbled ideas to a clear persuasive point.
자, 화면에 이미지가 하나 있습니다. "뒤죽박죽인 아이디어에서 명확하고 설득력 있는 요점으로"라고 되어 있네요.
We see this guy with a messy room.
지저분한 방에 있는 이 남자를 볼 수 있습니다.
He's torn over curtain there.
거기 커튼이 찢어져 있네요.
And it makes it look clean there.
그리고 그곳은 깨끗해 보이게 만듭니다.
It actually looks like mine.
사실 제 방처럼 보이네요.
All right, all right.
네, 네.
We have our arguments are like this, right?
우리의 주장은 이와 같습니다, 그렇죠?
Our arguments can be messy or they can be organized.
우리의 주장은 지저분할 수도 있고, 정리될 수도 있습니다.
And if our arguments are presented in an organized way, then we're more likely to convince people that something is true.
그리고 만약 우리의 주장이 정리된 방식으로 제시된다면, 우리는 사람들이 무언가가 사실이라고 설득할 가능성이 더 커집니다.
We want to do this genuinely. How can we genuinely organize our ideas to make a persuasive point?
우리는 이것을 진정성 있게 하고 싶습니다. 어떻게 하면 설득력 있는 요점을 만들기 위해 우리의 아이디어를 진정성 있게 정리할 수 있을까요?
Let's see if you can remember something about arguments or tell me what you think you know about persuasion.
주장에 대해 기억나는 것이 있는지, 아니면 설득에 대해 알고 있다고 생각하는 것을 말해주세요.
What are two parts of an argument that you remember?
기억나는 주장의 두 가지 부분은 무엇인가요?
Remember any specific parts?
특정 부분을 기억하시나요?
Actually, I can't remember it.
사실, 기억이 안 나요.
You know, like being so organized.
아시다시피, 그렇게 체계적인 거요.
And let me see the other one.
그리고 다른 하나는...
You said, organized.
'정리된'이라고 말씀하셨죠.
And messy.
그리고 '지저분한'.
Okay.
네.
And the opposite will be organized, right?
그리고 반대는 '정리된'이겠죠, 그렇죠?
So being organized versus his versus messy.
그래서 정리된 것 대 지저분한 것이죠.
How about the structure of an argument?
주장의 구조는 어떤가요?
How do you argue effectively?
어떻게 효과적으로 주장하나요?
What is something that you need to do in order to make a good argument?
좋은 주장을 하기 위해 해야 할 일은 무엇인가요?
Well, actually, I need to, I need to make it so comprehensive.
음, 사실, 저는 그것을 매우 포괄적으로 만들어야 합니다.
Right? For the person that is.
그렇죠? 그 사람을 위해서요.
Listen to one argument. Right?
하나의 주장을 듣는 거죠. 그렇죠?
And it has to be easy.
그리고 그것은 쉬워야 합니다.
To understand.
이해하기에요.
And easy to understand too.
그리고 이해하기도 쉬워야 하고요.
Agreed.
동의합니다.
So if we improve some of these aspects of grammar, like cohesion and flow, we can make it easier to understand.
그래서 만약 우리가 응집성이나 흐름과 같은 문법의 일부 측면을 개선한다면, 이해하기 더 쉽게 만들 수 있습니다.
We can make it organized and not messy.
우리는 그것을 지저분하지 않고 정리되게 만들 수 있습니다.
And we can make it whole. We can make it comprehensive.
그리고 우리는 그것을 완전하게 만들 수 있습니다. 포괄적으로 만들 수 있죠.
So these are our learning objectives for today's class.
이것들이 오늘 수업의 학습 목표입니다.
Can you read this first objective for us?
이 첫 번째 목표를 읽어주시겠어요?
Yeah, learning objectives for today.
네, 오늘의 학습 목표요.
Analyze a model argument for structure and flow.
구조와 흐름을 위해 모범 주장을 분석하기.
You want me to read all of them?
전부 다 읽을까요?
Okay.
네.
Utilize a graphic organizer to the construct arguments.
주장을 구성하기 위해 시각적 정리 도구를 활용하기.
Understand how grammatical choices impact clearly.
문법적 선택이 명확성에 어떻게 영향을 미치는지 이해하기.
And cohesion.
그리고 응집성.
Practice using transitional device says effectively.
전환 어구를 효과적으로 사용하는 연습하기.
And identify and correct common errors affecting argument clearly.
그리고 주장의 명확성에 영향을 미치는 흔한 오류를 식별하고 수정하기.
Alright, let's practice two of these words here.
좋습니다, 여기 이 두 단어를 연습해 봅시다.
This one is pronounced repeat after me clarity, clarity.
이것은 이렇게 발음합니다. 따라 해보세요. clarity, clarity.
Oh, clarity.
아, clarity.
Okay.
네.
And this one is with a Jen sound, like a Z.
그리고 이것은 Z와 같은 Jen 소리가 납니다.
ZJ kind of sound cohesion.
ZJ 같은 소리죠. cohesion.
Cohesion and clarity.
Cohesion과 clarity.
Okay.
네.
Yeah, I didn't notice it was.
네, 그게 그런 줄 몰랐어요.
The word as with clear.
clear와 같은 단어라는 것을요.
I confuse it actually.
사실 헷갈렸어요.
Yeah, it's related to the word clear.
네, clear라는 단어와 관련이 있습니다.
So clear.
그래서 clear.
Yeah, it's related.
네, 관련이 있죠.
The same thing.
같은 것이죠.
Right.
그렇죠.
That's what I think.
저는 그렇게 생각해요.
Uh huh.
네.
So you have clarity, which is the noun and something is clear.
그래서 명사형인 clarity가 있고, 무언가가 clear하다는 것은
It's the adjective.
형용사입니다.
Yeah.
네.
Alright.
좋습니다.
So what we can start off with first is the anatomy of an argument.
그럼 먼저 주장의 구성 요소부터 시작할 수 있습니다.
The different parts of an argument.
주장의 다른 부분들이죠.
And this is something that we can learn.
그리고 이것은 우리가 배울 수 있는 것입니다.
And remember from the days in school, when we would write essays and things like that.
그리고 학창 시절, 에세이를 쓰거나 그런 것들을 했던 날들을 기억해보세요.
How do you structure an essay?
에세이를 어떻게 구성하나요?
What comes first, next, and then last, when you write?
글을 쓸 때 무엇이 먼저 오고, 그 다음, 그리고 마지막에 오나요?
Let's read this part here.
여기 이 부분을 읽어봅시다.
Can you read this paragraph for me?
이 단락을 읽어주시겠어요?
Sure.
네.
A well crafted argument resembles a well engineered structure.
잘 만들어진 주장은 잘 설계된 구조물과 유사합니다.
It requires robust components and seamless connections.
견고한 구성 요소와 매끄러운 연결이 필요합니다.
Cohesion ensures ideas interlinked logically.
응집성은 아이디어들이 논리적으로 연결되도록 보장합니다.
While fluency allows the reader to navigate the argument smoothly.
반면 유창성은 독자가 주장을 매끄럽게 따라갈 수 있도록 합니다.
Okay, excellent.
네, 훌륭합니다.
So I made this image here to demonstrate this idea geometrically.
그래서 이 아이디어를 기하학적으로 보여주기 위해 이 이미지를 만들었습니다.
So we have the idea that an argument is complete.
그래서 우리는 주장이 완전하다는 아이디어를 가지고 있습니다.
But an argument can be complete, but not flow well.
하지만 주장은 완전할 수 있지만, 흐름이 좋지 않을 수 있습니다.
An argument can have all of the parts, but they're not put together.
주장은 모든 부분을 가질 수 있지만, 그것들이 제대로 연결되지 않을 수 있습니다.
So if we look at each stage of this, we see that it starts with a few elements that are not connected very well.
그래서 이것의 각 단계를 살펴보면, 처음에는 잘 연결되지 않은 몇 가지 요소들로 시작한다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
They're not connected via the reasoning that we need.
그것들은 우리가 필요로 하는 논리적 연결을 통해 연결되지 않았습니다.
We see that it starts to form, but it doesn't have good flow.
형태를 갖추기 시작하지만, 좋은 흐름이 없습니다.
And when the flow improves, we end with the perfect circle.
그리고 흐름이 개선되면, 완벽한 원으로 끝납니다.
So this illustrates the idea of a cohesion, which is it being whole.
그래서 이것은 응집성, 즉 전체적으로 완전하다는 아이디어를 보여줍니다.
The hexagon in this picture has cohesion, but it doesn't have flow.
이 그림의 육각형은 응집성은 있지만, 흐름은 없습니다.
This circle, on the other hand, has cohesion and has flow.
반면에 이 원은 응집성과 흐름을 모두 가지고 있습니다.
So how can we do that?
그럼 어떻게 그렇게 할 수 있을까요?
How can we structure our paragraphs and our essays?
어떻게 하면 우리의 단락과 에세이를 구성할 수 있을까요?
So that it is organized that it contains all of the parts that it needs.
그것이 정리되고, 필요한 모든 부분을 포함하도록요.
And so that it transitions from one part to the next logically.
그리고 한 부분에서 다음 부분으로 논리적으로 전환되도록요.
And if we do that right, if we do it effectively, then we have both of those elements and we strengthen our argument.
그리고 만약 우리가 그것을 제대로 한다면, 효과적으로 한다면, 우리는 그 두 가지 요소를 모두 갖게 되고 우리의 주장을 강화하게 됩니다.
So we have these argumentative elements, the puzzle pieces, cohesion, the connective structure, and the fluency, the smooth flow between ideas.
그래서 우리에게는 이러한 논증적 요소들, 즉 퍼즐 조각들, 응집성, 즉 연결 구조, 그리고 유창성, 즉 아이디어 간의 매끄러운 흐름이 있습니다.
All right. So we need to remember these core components of an argument.
네. 그래서 우리는 주장의 이러한 핵심 구성 요소들을 기억해야 합니다.
Let's read these here. Can you read these for me?
여기 이것들을 읽어봅시다. 이것들을 읽어주시겠어요?
Sure. Can I read it from the very beginning?
네. 처음부터 읽을까요?
Like recall the core components of an argument, claim, actually, background, ceases,
주장의 핵심 구성 요소 상기하기, 주장, 사실, 배경, 논지,
topic sentences, evidence, examples, potential, rebuttal,
주제 문장, 증거, 예시, 잠재적 반박,
and conclusion, a solid grasp of this element is foundational.
그리고 결론, 이 요소들에 대한 확실한 이해가 기본입니다.
Very good.
아주 좋습니다.
So we have the claim. Another word for claim is a thesis.
그래서 우리는 'claim'(주장)이 있습니다. 'claim'의 다른 말은 'thesis'(논지)입니다.
We have the background, which is the context of what we're talking about.
우리는 'background'(배경)가 있는데, 이것은 우리가 이야기하고 있는 것의 맥락입니다.
If we start talking and we start arguing, but nobody knows what we're talking about with the background of it, then it's not clear.
만약 우리가 이야기하기 시작하고 주장하기 시작하는데, 아무도 우리가 무엇에 대해 이야기하고 있는지, 그것의 배경이 무엇인지 모른다면, 그것은 명확하지 않습니다.
So we start with a claim.
그래서 우리는 'claim'(주장)으로 시작합니다.
We can give us some background information about that.
그것에 대한 배경 정보를 좀 줄 수 있습니다.
And then we have our thesis statement.
그리고 나서 우리는 'thesis statement'(논지 진술)를 갖습니다.
This is a thesis statement that is basically the main argument of the entire thing we're trying to convince the other person to believe.
이것은 기본적으로 우리가 상대방을 설득하여 믿게 하려는 전체 내용의 주요 주장인 논지 진술입니다.
So to persuade is to convince someone else to believe something.
그래서 설득한다는 것은 다른 누군가를 설득하여 무언가를 믿게 하는 것입니다.